<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AWSLambda on My First Step</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tags/awslambda/</link><description>Recent content in AWSLambda on My First Step</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>ja</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tags/awslambda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS CDK(v2): Enabling Lambda to read SystemManager's parameter store</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/enable_lambda_to_read_parameter_store/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/enable_lambda_to_read_parameter_store/</guid><description>If you want to use key information from outside AWS in Lambda, there is a way to pass it via the SystemManager parameter store. You can also pass it as an environment variable, but if you want to make it a bit more secure, this way seems to be better. You can easily specify the permissions to Lambda in the CDK.
Version node: 16.13.1 aws-cdk: 2.2.0 tsc: 4.5.4 HowTo Stack side On the Stack side, do grantRead() while passing the parameter name that you want to allow Lambda to read as an environment variable such as KEY_NAME.</description></item><item><title>AWS CDK(v2): Execute Lambda by Cron</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/lambda_cron_schedule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/lambda_cron_schedule/</guid><description>Using CDK, you can easily schedule Lambda to run using EventBridge. We will use the so-called cron method to describe the schedule.
One thing to be a little careful about is that a rule can be triggered multiple times in response to a single event. (From Official Troubleshooting). If you can manage that, it is very easy and useful.
Version node: 16.13.1 aws-cdk: 2.2.0 tsc: 4.5.4 HowTo For example, if you want to call myLambda every 10 minutes, you can write it as follows.</description></item><item><title>AWS CDK(v2): Linking Lambda and APIGateway</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/lambda_apigateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/lambda_apigateway/</guid><description>I think that Lambda and APIGateway are a combination that is often used, but is complicated to set up in the management console. It would be great to be able to write this easily. Also, if you write Lambda in TypeScript, it automatically transpiles the TypeScript and installs node modules and packages them for you, so it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to use.
Preparation It is assumed that the following settings have been completed.</description></item></channel></rss>