<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My First Step</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/</link><description>Recent content on My First Step</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>ja</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TypeScript: Create a file in any folder in GoogleDrive's TeamDrive</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/typescript/create_google_drive_file_in_team_drive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/typescript/create_google_drive_file_in_team_drive/</guid><description>Introduction While googleapis can be used to access various Google services, we note how to create files (e.g., Spreadsheet files ) in TeamDrive or any folder within it.
Version typescript: 4.6.3 googleapis: 100.0.0 How to create a file in any folder in GoogleDrive&amp;rsquo;s TeamDrive Install googleapis Install googleapis first.
npm install googleapis Creating a Service Account You will need a Google service account, so create one. You can find the procedure for creating a Google Service Account by searching for it.</description></item><item><title>AWS CDK(v2): Build AWSBatch environment for FARGATE_SPOT</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/aws_batch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/aws_batch/</guid><description>We will use AWS CDK v2 to build an AWSBatch environment for FARGATE_SPOT. To create an AWSBatch environment, we first create a
VPC ComputeEnvironment JobQueue for each task you want to run, and a
JobDefinition for each task you want to execute. I was not very familiar with this configuration and stumbled a lot, so it took me about a day the first time I made it&amp;hellip; Well, maybe next time I can do it in an hour or so.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Image on ECR to AWS App Runner with AWS CDK V2</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/apprunner_from_ecr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/apprunner_from_ecr/</guid><description>Deploy Image on ECR to AWS App Runner with AWS CDK V2</description></item><item><title>AWS CDK(v2): Enabling Lambda to read SystemManager's parameter store</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/enable_lambda_to_read_parameter_store/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/enable_lambda_to_read_parameter_store/</guid><description>If you want to use key information from outside AWS in Lambda, there is a way to pass it via the SystemManager parameter store. You can also pass it as an environment variable, but if you want to make it a bit more secure, this way seems to be better. You can easily specify the permissions to Lambda in the CDK.
Version node: 16.13.1 aws-cdk: 2.2.0 tsc: 4.5.4 HowTo Stack side On the Stack side, do grantRead() while passing the parameter name that you want to allow Lambda to read as an environment variable such as KEY_NAME.</description></item><item><title>AWS CDK(v2): Execute Lambda by Cron</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/lambda_cron_schedule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/lambda_cron_schedule/</guid><description>Using CDK, you can easily schedule Lambda to run using EventBridge. We will use the so-called cron method to describe the schedule.
One thing to be a little careful about is that a rule can be triggered multiple times in response to a single event. (From Official Troubleshooting). If you can manage that, it is very easy and useful.
Version node: 16.13.1 aws-cdk: 2.2.0 tsc: 4.5.4 HowTo For example, if you want to call myLambda every 10 minutes, you can write it as follows.</description></item><item><title>AWS CDK(v2): Basic Settings</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/first_step/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/first_step/</guid><description>AWS CDK v2 is a tool that enables you to create and modify AWS infrastructure configurations by writing them in a programming language. At first, it was a snap to do from the web admin console, but as it becomes more and more difficult to do the same thing over and over again (quickly and without mistakes and without getting frustrated), this kind of standardized system is useful once you get used to it.</description></item><item><title>AWS CDK(v2): Linking Lambda and APIGateway</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/lambda_apigateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/aws_cdk_v2/lambda_apigateway/</guid><description>I think that Lambda and APIGateway are a combination that is often used, but is complicated to set up in the management console. It would be great to be able to write this easily. Also, if you write Lambda in TypeScript, it automatically transpiles the TypeScript and installs node modules and packages them for you, so it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to use.
Preparation It is assumed that the following settings have been completed.</description></item><item><title>About This Blog</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/etc/my_first_step/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/etc/my_first_step/</guid><description>This blog is about the &amp;ldquo;first steps&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;introduction&amp;rdquo; that I have made. I often search the web wondering what it&amp;rsquo;s like, if it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a hassle, if it&amp;rsquo;s going to cost money, if I can try it out, and so on.
That&amp;rsquo;s 10% of my motivation.
The other 20% is because I was curious about how much advertising income there is from blogs.
The remaining 70% is because I want to donate the money I earn (if I can earn it) as a way to repay the fortune of being in a position where I might be able to earn advertising income (I&amp;rsquo;m serious).</description></item><item><title>Starting a Blog with Hugo</title><link>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/hugo/start_blog_with_hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.my-first-step.info/en/tech/hugo/start_blog_with_hugo/</guid><description>This is the result of my research on how to start a free (or low-cost) blog where people who are somewhat PC-savvy can post ads.</description></item></channel></rss>